[
{
  "question": "Describe the difference between Lagrangian and Eulerian frameworks and which would be more useful in modeling the flow of fluid through a pipe fixture.",
  "answer": "Lagrangian framework proposes following the movement of every single particle within a fluid. This allows one to easily apply Newton's laws of physics to said particles. Eulerian framework, on the other hand, focuses on the field in which the fluid flows, modeling fluid quantities as a function of their position in space. This allows one to more easily model large numbers of fluid particles, which Lagrangian is much less capable of doing, by discerning the fluids relative velocity as a function of their position in space. As such, for a large mass of fluid flowing through a pipe wherein our focus would likely be on mass flow, of which velocity plays a key role in, it would be more appropriate to utilize an Eulerian framework to properly discern the fluid's velocity profile.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Does a temperature increase always correlate to a decreaes in viscosity in all fluids? If not, explain why.",
  "answer": "No. Increased temperature in a liquid does serve to decrease its viscosity as increased temperature causes an increase in kinetic energy and hence more vibrations that will allow particles to slide past one another much easier. However, this is not the same case with gases. In gases, increased temperature also increases kinetic energy, but this increase correlates to a higher particle collision rate, which in turn produces more resistance to movement, and hence higher viscosity. As temprature increasess, viscosity of liquids decrease, and viscosity of gases increase. Although this is almost contradictory, it must be understood, since gases and liquids should therefore be treated differently when it comes to assessing their viscous effects on flow.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Describe Bernoulli's Equation, its assumptions, and a use case.",
  "answer": "Bernoulli's Equation is the fundamental equation regarding following the flow of a fluid along a streamline, relating pressure, density, and velocity in one compact equation. Given quantities at one point, we can always determine the quantities at another point, provided they are connected by the same streamline. The main assumptions made are that the flow is isentropic, that no heat is being added to the system, and that the flow is incompressible. A good use case is determining the difference in flow quantities on two sides of an orifice. We can measure the pressure and velocity on one side and given a fixed temperature, the density of the fluid will not change. Now, given either velocity or pressure, we can work out the missing quantities. Change in height can also be easily factored in to the equation if it is pertinent.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "What is the difference between static and stagnation pressure, and how would you measure them?",
  "answer": "Static pressure is the pressure of the fluid as it is in motion, or retains its velocity. Stagnation pressure is the pressure of the fluid if it were to be isentropically slowed to rest. To measure them, you would use two different types of pitot tubes. One is an invasive design, where the pitot tube is inserted into the flow and aligned parallel to the flow. This allows measurement of stagnation pressure by reducing velocity of the stream to zero. To measure static pressure, you would use a pitot tube aligned perpendicular to the flow without extending into the flow. This prevents stagnation of the flow and thus you are able to measure the pressure of the flow without altering its velocity.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "What is the difference between an extensive and an intensive property, and list some corresponding examples.",
  "answer": "The only difference between extensive and intensive properties is that extensive properties change as the amount of the matter changes, such as mass or volume. Intensive properties, on the other hand do not change as more matter is added, such as temperature or pressure. However, extensive properties can be normalized to their intensive counterparts, such as specific volume, by dividing the value by mass. This works because it now tells us the characteristics of the matter as an intrinsic value related to the mass, which is the defnition of an intensive property. This can be extremely useful, such as when determining specific impulse, where it is normal to compare engine efficiency as a function of their impulse relative to vehicle mass, which aids in unbiased analysis of propulsion systems.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "What is the main concern when attempting to determine fluid flow behavior in high differential pressure testing?",
  "answer": "The main concern is choking the flow. When the differential between downstream and upstream pressures reaches a certain level, the flow becomes choked, wherein the mass flow through the choked area does not change, no matter how much differential pressure is increased. This makes it near-impossible to record accurate and meaningful data past the point of choked flow. The best way to avoid choked flow is to prevent the main contributing factors. That is: length of the pipe, smallest area of pipe, and skin friction coefficient. The longer the pipe, the smaller the area of the pipe, and the higher the skin friction coefficient, the more likely flow is to choke. When flow is choked, the mass flow through the pipe does not increase, no matter how much the downstream pressure is decreased.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Why are gas property tables so important in the study of thermodynamics?",
  "answer": "We use gas property tables to relate Mach number to ratios between pressure, temperature, and density, as well as data for specific Mach and gamma (ratio of specific heat capacity to specific enthalpy) relations since those equations are extremely difficult to solve numerically. Without these tables, which are solved for graphically instead of numerically, we can easily locate and utilize values to solve questions much more quickly than we would be able to otherwise. This is only possbile because of our equations are only dependent on two factors, gamma, which is the ratio between specific heat capacities at constant pressure and volume, and Mach number, which are both easily recognizable values. This makes navigating and using a gas property table much simpler and therefore so much more effective.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "What are the assumptions required in order to derive equations for fluid flow across a shock wave?",
  "answer": "Fluid flow through a shock wave is non-isentropic, meaning it is irreversible, since the flow is still adiabatic as it does not transfer or gain energy from its surroundings. However, mass, momentum, and energy are conserved across a shock wave, and we can therefore employ equations for this. Using continuity (conservation of mass), conservation of momentum, and conservation of energy equations in their isentropic forms to determine the change in Mach number across a shock using the following relation: (energy * continuity)/(momentum^2). From here, we can then substitute downstream Mach into the conservation equations, and rearranging will provide upstream-downstream relations for temperature, pressurem, and fluid density in compressible flow, which is extremely useful in solving for quantities as fluid flows through a shock wave.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Describe entropy and why it is useful.",
  "answer": "Entropy, the inability of a system's thermal energy to yield useful work, is an extensive property that outlines the disorderliness of a system. The higher the entropy of the system, more disordered it is and the less energy there is that can perform useful mechanical work. Generally, entropy can not be measured as a state variable as it is not a physical quantity, but the difference between two states can be determined in order to generate powerful relations in the form of T-s diagrams, relating temperature to entropy and in turn allowing us to make sense of isobaric and isochoric processes. This allows one to determine certain pressure, temperature, and volume relations in accordance with isentropic changes in state. This also allows us to determine the irreversibility of processes. If entropy increases within a system, it cannot return to a lower state of entropy without applying work to the system. This is apparent in T-S diagrams, when a process increases in entropy the process is irreversible.",
  "explanation": "",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "How much work is required to compress an ideal diatomic gas isobarically at 2.5 x 10^5 Pa from an initial volume of 0.015 m^3 to a final volume of 0.010 m^3?",
  "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    P = 250000\n    V_1 = 0.015\n    V_2 = 0.01\n    W = P * (V_1 - V_2)\n    print(str(W), 'J')\n    ",
  "explanation": "Given: Isobaric, so constant pressure, and the gas is ideal. Now we can derive the equations to solve this problem. Work = W, Pressure = P, Force = F, Area = A, Volume = V, Displacement = d. W = F * dx, F = P * A, W = P * A * dx, A * dx = dV, W = P * dV",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Suppose an aerospace engineer wants to determine the skin friction coefficient in a section of 50 cm diameter piping. They perform a series of tests, wherein the values are as follows: Mach number entering the section is 1.5 and length to choked flow is 3 m. How can they determine the skin friction coefficient? List any assumptions made.",
  "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    fourcfL_D = 0.1361\n    D = 0.5\n    L = 3\n    cf = (0.1361*0.5) / (4*3)\n    print(str(cf))\n    ",
  "explanation": "Assuming the flow is viscous and compressible, to achieve choked flow conditions, one can use the following equation: (4*cf*L)/D, where D = diameter, L = length and cf = skin friction coefficient. Then, using a table to determine the value at Mach 1.5, we get 0.1361. This is the number we plug into the equation before. This allows us to rearrange and solve for cf.",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "If the average human mouth inlet area is 45 cm^2 and the density of orange juice is 15.7 g/cm^3, find the mass flow if the orange juice is entering Dave's mouth at 195 ft/min.",
  "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    rho = 15.7\n    v = 195\n    A = 45\n    v1 = 195 * (1/60) * (0.3048/1) * (100/1) #converts ft/min to cm/s\n    m_dot = rho * v1 * A\n    print(str(m_dot), 'g/s')\n    ",
  "explanation": "Mass flow can be determined by M_dot = rho * v * A where rho = density, v = velocity, A = area.",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Elmo and Cookie Monster's houses are a comfortable 20 and sweltering 35 degrees Celsius respectively. If the mass flow rate between the two houses is 0.035 kg/s, what is the energy input needed in order to bring the two rooms to an equilibrium temperature?",
  "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    T1 = 273.15 + 20\n    T2 = 273.15 + 35\n    T_av = (T2-T1)/2\n    deltaT = np.abs(T_av - T1)\n    m_dot = 0.035\n    cp = 1003.5\n    Q_dot = cp*m_dot*deltaT\n    print(str(Q_dot), 'kW')\n    ",
  "explanation": "Assuming air as a perfect gas, cp = 1003.5 J/(kg*s)  We first need to convert the temperature to degrees Kelvin, then we find the average and determine the change in temperature for each house (which should be the same, just in opposite directions). Then, we use SFEE, wherein we can zero out the work, kinetic, and potential energy terms. Thus we are left with Q_dot (power) Q_dot=m_dot*(he-hi), which can be substituted for m_dot*cp(Te-Ti) or m_dot*cp(deltaT) to solve for Q_dot in units of kW.",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Two adjacent pipes of diameter d at Hershey's Chocolate Factory are flowing coolant with density of 0.001112 kg/m^3 into a larger pipe of diameter 3d connecting the two inlet pipes. The incoming free-stream velocity is V and 2V respectively. Given the pressure at the outlet after the flow is completely mixed is 20 psi and V = 8 m/s, what is the incoming pressure in each pipe if both pipes have the same pressure.",
  "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    rho = 0.001112\n    d = 1\n    V = 8\n    p2 = 20\n    A1 = (np.pi*d*d)/4 #Area of 1 inlet pipe\n    A2 = (np.pi*(3*d)*(3*d))/4 #Area of outlet pipe\n    m_dot1 = rho * V * A1\n    m_dot2 = rho * 2 * V * A1\n    V_o = (m_dot1 + m_dot2)/(rho * A2)\n    m_dotout = rho * V_o * A2\n    p1 = (m_dotout * V_o - (m_dot1 * V + m_dot2 * 2 * V) + p2 * A2) / (2 * A1)\n    print(str(p1), 'psi')\n    ",
  "explanation": "Assume incompressible and steady flow and ignore viscous effects. Using conservation of mass, we set m_dot = rho * V * (pi*d^2)/4, such that m_dotin = m_dotout becomes m_dot1 + m_dot2 = m_dotout => rho * V * (pi*d^2)/4 + rho * 2V * (pi*d^2)/4 = rho * V_o * (pi*(3d)^2)/4. Solve for V_o. Then, we can use conservation of momentum to determine the incoming static pressures. F + sum(p*A) = sum(m_dot*v) => 0 + p1 * 2*(pi*(d)^2)/4 - p2 * (pi*(3d)^2)/4 = m_dotout * V_o - m_dot1 * V - m_dot2 * 2V. Rearrange, plug in values and solve to find p1. (Diameter of the pipe is not given, but we can see it cancels out in the equation, so plugging in 1 in the calculations will not affect the results.)",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "If SpaceX's Raptor engines have a specific impulse of 380 s, using air cp = 1.005 kJ/(kg*K) and inlet temperature of 525 degrees Kelvin, what is the Mach number of flow input required",
  "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    I_sp = 380\n    cp = 1.005\n    T_0 = 525\n    val = np.sqrt(cp * T_0)\n    imp = I_sp / val\n    print(str(imp))\n    #Find this number in gas properties table and we get that the Mach number is between Mach 0.2 and 0.3\n    ",
  "explanation": "Since specific impulse is just F/m_dot, we can use F/(m_dot * sqrt(cp * T_0)) to determine the value we need to reference in our gas properties table, assuming gamma is 1.4 for an ideal diatomic gas (air). This will provide us the correct Mach number the input flow should enter the engine at for our given inlet conditions.",
  "reference": ""
},
{
  "question": "Graph the relationships between isobaric, isochoric, isentropic, adiabatic, and isothermal processes on T-dS and P-V diagrams.",
  "answer": "\n    import numpy as np\n    import matplotlib.pyplot as plt\n    plt.plot([2,2],[1,12],'b-',[5,5],[6,19],'b-',[1,2,3,4],[6,8,12,18],'r--',[3,4,5,7,8],[3,4,5,11,16],'r--',[1,2,4,6],[8,8.5,10,13],'g--',[4,5,7,9],[5,5.5,7.5,10],'g--')\n    plt.axis([0, 10, 0, 20])\n    plt.text(3,15,'P2')\n    plt.text(7,13,'P1')\n    plt.text(8,8,'V1')\n    plt.text(4,11,'V2')\n    plt.text(2.25,5,'S1')\n    plt.text(5.25,18,'S2')\n    plt.title('T-S Graph')\n    plt.gca().get_xaxis().set_visible(False)\n    plt.gca().get_yaxis().set_visible(False)\n    plt.plot([2,3,5,7,9],[17,11,8,7,6.5],'y-',[2,3,4,5,7,9],[16,8,6,5,3.5,3]'y-',[2,3,4,5,7,9],[18,15,12,11,10,9.5],'y-',[4,5,6,7,9],[12,9,7,5.5,3],'p--')\n    plt.axis([1, 10, 0, 20])\n    plt.text(6,12,'Isothermal processes')\n    plt.text(8,2,'T1')\n    plt.text(8,7.5,'T2')\n    plt.text(8,10.5,'T3')\n    plt.text(6.5,4.5,'Adiabatic process')\n    plt.title('P-V Graph')\n    plt.gca().get_xaxis().set_visible(False)\n    plt.gca().get_yaxis().set_visible(False)\n    ",
  "explanation": "Isobaric means constant pressure, isochoric means constant volume, and isentropic means constant entropy. Thus, on a T-S diagram, I would graph an isentropic process as a vertical line. For isobaric and isochoric processes, they would be shaped like a second order polynomial, with isobaric being steeper than isochoric due to the behavior of the TdS equations. TdS=dU+vdP and TdS=dH-vdP. Replacing dH and dU with CpdT and CvdT, we can see that the slope of the isochoric process will be greater than the isobaric process, as denoted by the V lines as opposed to the P lines. In a P-V diagram, the isotherms (T) represent constant temperature processes, while the blue dashed line represents an adiabatic one, as even though there is no heat exchange between the system and its surroundings, the system still may change temperature, as seen by the adiabatic process line crossing the isotherms.",
  "reference": ""
}
]